&gt；&gt；扬声器1：关于吊装的最后一个注意事项。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 1: One last note on hoisting.
你们中的一些人以前听过这句话，
Some of you have heard the phrase before,
让不提升关于块范围。
let doesn't hoist with respect to the block scope.
因为当你写这样的代码时，老师在第2行的作业
Because when you write code like this, the teacher assignment on line 2
会抛出一个错误，一个所谓的TDZ错误，临时死区错误，好吗？
will throw an error, a so-called TDZ error, temporal dead zone error, okay?
这句话，让我们不要举起，
This statement, let doesn't hoist,
是出于好的精神，但它是不准确的。
is meant in good spirit, but it is inaccurate.
我可以向你证明这是不准确的，因为我们已经看到
And I can prove to you that it's inaccurate, because we've already seen
提升的概念，我们已经看到了一个代码示例。
a notion of hoisting and we've already seen a code example.
如果老师没有被提升，因此还不存在于范围内，
Where if teacher didn't get hoisted and therefore didn't exist in the scope yet,
那么程序的行为就会有所不同。
then the program would behave differently.
所以这里有一个这样的例子。
So here is such an example.
在这段代码中，如果第5行的老师没有主持，
In this code, if the teacher on line 5 did not host,
然后第4行应该打印出“Kyle”。
then line 4 should print out "Kyle".
因为在第4行没有教师，它应该转到外部范围和
Because there is no teacher as of line 4 and it should go to the outer scope and
找到第1行中的变量。
find the variable from line 1.
但此代码仍然抛出TDZ错误，并且
But this code still throws a TDZ error, and
它仍然抛出TDZ错误的原因是因为let和consts仍然提升。
the reason it still throws a TDZ error is because lets and consts still hoist.
但它们的升降方式是不同的。
But there is a difference between how they hoist.
第一，let和const只提升到一个块，而vars提升到一个函数。
Number one, lets and consts only hoist to a block, whereas vars hoist to a function.
但是第二，这是更重要的事情，
But number two, and this is the more important thing,
var和let const之间区别是var，当它创建
the difference between var and let const is that var, when it creates
它的变量，并在编译时为您的作用域制定计划。
its variables and has the plan during the compile time for your scope.
它说在这个范围内会有一个叫做教师的变量，
And it says there's gonna be a variable called teacher in this scope,
它还说当作用域开始时，将其初始化为undefined。
it also says when the scope starts, initialize it to undefined.
&gt；&gt；Speaker 1：当let将其变量提升到其块范围内时，它表示
&gt;&gt; Speaker 1: When let hoists its variables into its block scope it says
创建一个名为Teacher的位置，但不要初始化它。
create a location called teacher, but don't initialize it.
它处于未初始化状态，
It is in an uninitialized state,
未初始化与未定义不同。
uninitialized being different than undefined.
未初始化意味着您还不能触摸它。
Uninitialized meaning you can't touch it yet.
直到您在该块中遇到let或
And it doesn't get initialized until in that block you run across the let or
常量声明。
the const declaration.
&GT；&GT；扬声器1：所以这些绝对是吊装的，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 1: So these absolutely do hoist,
这就是为什么我们仍然收到TDZ错误，只是它们没有初始化。
which is why we still get a TDZ error, it's just that they don't get initialized.
&gt；&gt；扬声器1：顺便问一下，有时有人问我为什么TDZ错误？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 1: By the way, I sometimes get asked why the TDZ error?
他们为什么犯了一个错误？
Why did they make this an error?
它的细微差别比你可能意识到的要多得多。
It is much more nuance than you might realize.
我过去认为在这种情况下TDZ错误的主要原因
I used to believe that the primary reason for the TDZ error in this scenario
本质上是，TC39试图让你成为社会工程师。
was that, essentially, TC39 was trying to socially engineer you.
停止在作用域中早于声明变量的位置为变量赋值。
To stop assigning to variables earlier in scopes than where you've declared them.
同样，我大体上同意这一点，但当一种语言是如此的时候，我会有点恼火
Which again, I generally agree with, but I'm a little annoyed when a language is so
粗暴地表达自己的观点，好吗？
heavy handed with its opinions, okay?
所以我大体上会同意这一点，而且我过去只是有点胡说八道
So I generally would agree with that, and I used to just sort of chaff
一想到他们会强迫我做出那个决定。
at the idea that they would have forced me into that decision.
但事实证明，这比那要细微得多。
But turns out it's much more nuance than that.
这几乎是学术细微差别的高度，
This is almost the height of kind of academic nuance,
但我会和你分享它，让你对TDZ有一个完整的看法。
but I'll share it with you so that you have the full perspective on TDZ.
TDZ存在的原因甚至不是因为let，TDZ存在是因为const。
The reason TDZ exists is not even for let, TDZ exists because of const.
考虑在块范围内附加const。
Think about const being attached inside of a block scope.
想象一下，如果const将自身初始化为undefined。
Imagine if const initialized itself to undefined.
然后在块的第1行，您对该变量执行console.log，然后
And then on line 1 of a block, you did console.log of that variable and
您看到它未定义，然后您看到它的值为42。
you saw it undefined, and then later you saw it with the value 42.
从技术上讲，const在两个不同的时间有两个不同的值，
Technically, that const would have had two different values at two different times,
这在学术上违反了常量的概念。
which academically violates the concept of a const.
所以他们说我们必须防止你在作用域的早期访问变量
So they said we have to prevent you from accessing a variable earlier in the scope
当它被分配一个且只有一个值时，所以
than when it's been assigned that one and only one value, so
在中间状态下你不能观察到它。
that you can't observe it in that intermediate state.
所以他们为const发明了TDZ，然后他们说，
So they invented TDZ for const and then they said, well,
如果我们要为const做，我们也可以为let做。
if we're gonna do it for const, we might as well do it for let.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：[听不到]&gt；&gt；扬声器1：这是事实。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: [INAUDIBLE] &gt;&gt; Speaker 1: That's the fact.
所以让我们有一个TDZ，因为const在学术上需要一个TDZ。
So let's have a TDZ, because const academically needed a TDZ.
我的建议？
My advice?
就像我之前说的，把你所有的字母，或者如果你真的坚持
Just exactly as I said before, put all your lets, or if you really insist on
冒号，把他们都放在最顶端，在第一行。
colons, put them all at the very top of the block, on the very first line.
然后你就永远无法观察到TDZ了
And then you'll never be able to observe a TDZ.
[笑]不要把它们串在那些范围内，那是个坏主意。
[LAUGH] Don't string them throughout those scopes, that's a bad idea.
这样我们就不会说话了
Just so that we don't say things,
有些人有时会在这些话题上与我意见相左。
and I have people that sometimes will disagree with me on these topics.
这样我们就能完全清楚这个话题是不是或者
And just so that we're entirely clear on this topic of whether or
不让不升起。
not let doesn't hoist.
这里实际上是在规范中，它说变量是在它们的
Here is actually in the spec where it says that the variables are created when their
实例化包含词汇环境。
containing lexical environment is instantiated.
在计算词法绑定时，而不是在创建变量时。
When the lexical binding is evaluated, not when the variable's created.
所以它就在说明书里。
So it's right there in the spec.
最近有一场很大的推特大战，人们告诉我错了
There was a big Twitter war recently where people were telling me that I was wrong on
说明书上就是这么说的。
this, and that's what it says in the spec.
即使我们可能希望有不同的心理模型，
Even though we might like to have different mental models for it,
说明书上是这么说的。
it's what it says in the spec.
&gt；&gt；Speaker 3：为什么函数表达式不提升？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Why do function expressions not hoist?
我们可以在编译时与运行时的上下文中讨论这一点吗？
Could we talk about that in the context of compile time versus run time?
&gt；&gt；扬声器1：好的。&gt；&gt；扬声器3：发生的事情
&gt;&gt; Speaker 1: Okay. &gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Things that happen for
函数表达式。
the function expression.
&gt；&gt；演讲者1：是的，这是一个好问题。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a good question.
所以我不知道我能不能找到那张幻灯片，但如果你回想起来，
So I don't know if I could find the slide, but if you recall back,
当您将函数表达式赋给变量时，
when you assign a function expression to a variable,
变量装饰本身提升了，但赋值是运行时的事情。
the variables decoration itself hoisted, but the assignment is a run time thing.
想象一下JavaScript对可执行代码重新排序的想法。
Imagine mentally the idea of JavaScript reordering your executable code.
我们很快就会陷入混乱，对吧？
We would quickly descend into chaos, right?
所以可执行代码不能在概念上重新排序，只能是声明性代码。
So executable code can't conceptually be reordered, only declarative code.
所以我们可以说有一个叫X的东西，或者一个叫老师的东西，还有
So we can say that there is a thing called X, or a thing called teacher, and
即使有一个叫做X的东西，它也会引用这个函数作用域。
even there is a thing called X that's gonna reference this function scope.
我们可以声明性地做到这一点。
We can do that declaratively.
但如果它是可以作为执行操作观察到的东西
But if it's something that is literally observable as an execution operation
在程序中，不能提升，不能在编译时发生。
in a program, that can't hoist, that can't happen at compile time.
它必须在运行时发生。
It has to happen at run time.
它必须发生在程序中通常会发生的地方。
And it has to happen where in the program it would normally happen.
否则，您将永远无法预测您的JavaScript。
Otherwise you would never be able to predict your JavaScript.
&gt；&gt；Speaker 3：因此，如果在运行时指定函数表达式
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: So at run time if you're assigning a function expression
针对可变目标，
to a variable targeting,
那么在该运行时过程中是否创建了一个新的作用域？
then is a new scope created during that run time process?
&gt；&gt；演讲者1：好吧，让我们把话说清楚。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 1: Well, let's be clear.
你问的是一个非常重要的问题，但上面有两层。
You're asking a very important question, but there's this two layered on top.
第一，编译时仍然处理函数。
Number one, compile time still handled the function.
它没有推迟处理，
It didn't defer handling,
它不像它说的那样，我不知道那里有一个函数。
it's not like it said I don't know that there's a function there.
它仍然是一个函数，它仍然需要有一个计划，
It's still a function, it still has to have a plan,
它的彩色弹珠和所有其他东西的地图。
a map for its colored marbles and all of that other stuff.
没有发生的是它在编译时没有得到，
What didn't happen is it didn't get, at compile time,
与作用域中的某个标识符关联，但它仍然被编译了，好吗？
associated with some identifier in the scope, but it still got compiled, okay?
所以这是第一位。
So that's number one.
第二，所有功能都有其范围的计划，直到，
Number two, all functions have a plan for their scope, until,
每次他们被处死。
and every time they get executed.
因此，无论它是声明还是表达式，当它被执行时
So whether it was a declaration or an expression, when it gets executed is when
整个地图绘制计划在记忆中变成了真实的东西，而且
that whole mapper plan becomes a real thing in memory, and
每次它被执行，情况就是这样。
every time it gets executed, that is the case.
所以这在声明和表达式之间没有区别。
So that's no different between declarations or expressions.